Guilherme Silveira dos Santos

Florianopolis, BR guilherme@giox.com.br Phone: +55 (48) 9640-3883

Resumo

I am a Computer Engineer since 2011, but I started programming long time before that. I have always been learning new things and I can do it very quickly. I started studying PHP at home when I was 13, since that, I never stopped using it. During the college and internships I learned other programming languages, such as C/C++, Java and Lua.

I've been working long time as a freelancer developer and most of the time involving web development, as a result I became an experienced web developer with big expertise in PHP, JavaScript, CSS and HTML.

In my spare time I've contributed in many open source projects like Enlightenment Foundation Libraries (EFL), Zend Framework and Backbone.js.

I worked in many companies with several technologies and it made me an open minded developer, with can-do attitude and a good interpersonal relationship. Currently I'm working as Full Stack Developer in south Brazil, but looking for new challenges around the world.

Educação

UNIVALI University, BSc in Computer Engineering, June 2011.

Experiência

GIOX Tecnologia

Apr 2013 - Present

CEO and Full Stack Developer

Main Technologies: PHP, JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Linux, Git;

I'm the main developer of an ERP (Enterprise Resource Planning) system created by GIOX Tecnologia. The backend was developed using PHP and MySQL, the frontend using HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript. Communication with some Web Services. Development of REST API. Some libraries used: Zend Framework 2, PHPUnit, Doctrine2, Boostrap3, jQuery and Backbone.js.

uTech Tecnologia

Nov 2014 - Feb 2015

 $Out sourced\ Developer$

Main Technologies: C++/QT/QML, JavaScript, SIP;

This was an outsourced project to develop a Softphone. It became part of company's platform. The biggest challenge was be multi-platform, running in Windows 7, Linux and Mac OS X. The software was developed using C++, QML and JavaScript through Qt library and PJSIP as SIP stack.

Digitro Tecnologia

Dec 2009 - Mar 2013

Software Engineer

Main Technologies: C/C++, Lua, Shell Script, Linux, SIP;

Embedded development of an IP Phone touch screen with color display using Blackfin processor with uCLinux distribution. We used u-boot, EFL graphic library, GLib, GObject, GDBus, CppUTest and Sofia-SIP as SIP stack.

Speaker recognition: Web service responsible for creating audio models from the voice and storing it. The voice models where used later to identify someone talking on a audio recording. Tools used: Lua, lighthttpd, GStreamer, fastcgi, MongoDB.

Keyword spotting: Middleware used to perform text search on audio using a proprietary protocol to communicate with clients. Tools used: Lua, C, GStreamer.

Flash Audio streaming server: Web service responsible for loading audio recordings in different audio codecs, transcode then, apply filters and effects and send to the client through the RTMP protocol. Tools used: C++, C, GStreamer, Monit.

Habilidades

Progamming Languages: PHP, JavaScript, C/C++, Java, Lua;

 $Databases: \ {\bf MySQL}, \ {\bf MongoDB}, \ {\bf plus} \ {\bf some} \ {\bf experience} \ {\bf with} \ {\bf Postgres};$

Agile practices: TDD, SCRUM, Kanban, Pair programming, Clean code;

Languages: Fluent in Portuguese, Intermediate in English and Spanish;

Tools: Phing, Grunt, Ansible, Vagrant, Docker, Jenkins;

Outras informações

• Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/guilhermesilveirasantos/en

 $\bullet \ \, \textbf{Github} \colon \text{https://github.com/guilherme-santos} \\$